Milepost to Self-Government Oral History Project OHP013
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Milepost to Self-Government Oral History Project
1993
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
District of Columbia. Public Library
OHP013
0.75 Linear feet
2 Boxes
Arrangement
Series 1: Transcripts Scope and Contents Materials in this series include transcripts of the panel discussion and interview. There is no transcript for 12-03. Series 2: Interviews Scope and Contents Materials in this series include master and patron copies of the panel discussion and interviews on audio cassette.
Biographical / Historical
The DC Public Library was founded in 1896 by an act of Congress "to furnish books and other printed matter and information service convenient to the homes and offices of all residents of the District.
Custodial History
The D.C. Public Library conducted these interviews and panel discussion as a part of the Annual Conference of Washington D.C. Historical Studies Conference in 1993. Tapes and transcripts were officially transferred to the Library shortly after their completion. There is no transfer documentation between Library departments.
Scope and Contents
On February 27, 1993, the DC Public Library held a public panel entitled "Milestone on the Road to Self-Government." The panel was part of the 20th Annual Conference on Washington, D.C. Historical Studies. Panelists included John Bonner Duncan, Walter E. Washington, John Hechinger, and Charles Horsky, prominent D.C. politicians who played key roles in the city's transition from the three-commissioner-led government to home rule in 1973. The panel was recorded and a separate interview was conducted in 1993 with Hechinger in which he reflects on his life, business, race relations, and his role as the District's first Chairman of the City Council. The latter was part of a planned post-World War II Washington documentation project led by the Library and the D.C. Archives. The two sets of recordings were later combined into a single oral history project focused on documenting and interpreting the political development of a major metropolitan community since the end of World War II. The project includes audio recordings and transcripts of a panel discussion of the transition to home rule and a follow-up interview with one of the panelists. Topics include the formation of the D.C. city government, D.C.'s relationship with the federal government, the roles of interviewees in business and government, and race relations.
Oral History; Home rule -- Washington (D.C.)
- Series 1: Transcripts
  Scope and Contents
  Materials in this series include transcripts the panel discussion and interview. There is no transcript for 12-03.
  - Charles Tignor Duncan, John Bonner Duncan, Walter Edward Washington, John Walter Hechinger, Charles Antone Horsky, 1993 February 27 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - John Hechinger, 1993 July 30 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series 2: Interviews
  Materials in this series include master and patron copies of the panel discussion and interview on audio cassette.
  - Charles Tignor Duncan, John Bonner Duncan, Walter Edward Washington, John Walter Hechinger, Charles Antone Horsky, 1993 February 27 (Box 2, Folder 13-01)
  - Charles Tignor Duncan, John Bonner Duncan, Walter Edward Washington, John Walter Hechinger, Charles Antone Horsky, 1993 February 27 (Box 2, Folder 13-01)
  - Charles Tignor Duncan, John Bonner Duncan, Walter Edward Washington, John Walter Hechinger, Charles Antone Horsky, 1993 February 27 (Box 2, Folder 13-01)
  - John Hechinger, 1993 July 30 (Box 2, Folder 13-02)
  - John Hechinger, 1993 July 30 (Box 2, Folder 13-02)
  - 2nd Milepost on the Road to Self Government (Box 2, Folder 13-03)